<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cherrytree>
  <node name="Footprinting" unique_id="28" prog_lang="custom-colors" tags="" readonly="0" nosearch_me="0" nosearch_ch="0" custom_icon_id="0" is_bold="0" foreground="" ts_creation="1704148315" ts_lastsave="1704148747">
    <rich_text>Tools

WireShark - Can be used to listen to packets and network traffic. From here you can save a PCAP, and filter (statistics &gt; endpoints)

ARP-SCAN - can be used to sweep ARP broadcasts to listen to discover what is connected (can use MAC to determine device type)

Ping - will let you know if the device is online using ICMP requests will also inform you of the latency which can tell you location

FPing - similar to ping, but can be sent to multiple hosts at one time (you can filter out errors with 2&gt;/dev/null)

Nmap - available on all OS, learned about in active recon chapter

ZenMap - zenmap is nmap, but with a GUI, it's opensource and free, and available on all OS zmap - not discussed in this video, but zmap is a version of nmap, with slightly less functionality, but can run faster.

PortScanning can be used to Identify Operating Systems and accessible services. Doing this is very loud, and will lead to detection, but is allowed in a PenTest

Use footprinting, to establish services, by examining the responses from hosts, and checks against a signature database. Some OS are more obvious than others, and some services will explicitly tell us what OS this is installed on.

If the port is open: syn &gt; syn/ack &gt; ack

If the port is open syn &gt; ack

Nmap includes a stealthy scan. (used to evade IDS) syn &gt; syn/ack &gt; RST

UDP scans are slower, response open|filtered can be sped up by increasing rate (min-rate)

Nmap Automator, can run new scans and continue enumerating further, rustscan is fast and made out of rust, and autorecon which will tell you everthing you can know from scanning.

</rich_text>
    <rich_text link="webs https://github.com/21y4d/nmapAutomator">https://github.com/21y4d/nmapAutomator</rich_text>
    <rich_text>




</rich_text>
    <codebox char_offset="1649" justification="left" frame_width="500" frame_height="70" width_in_pixels="1" syntax_highlighting="sh" highlight_brackets="1" show_line_numbers="0">./nmapAutomator.sh --host 10.1.1.1 --type All
./nmapAutomator.sh -H 10.1.1.1 -t Basic
./nmapAutomator.sh -H academy.htb -t Recon -d 1.1.1.1
./nmapAutomator.sh -H 10.10.10.10 -t network -s ./nmap</codebox>
  </node>
</cherrytree>
